Now let's discuss a little bit about
الآن، هيا نتحدث قليلًا عن
strategies to send winning expression of interests to the client.
طرق واستراتيجيات إرسال التعبير عن الاهتمام بالعمل إلى العميل.
To quickly refresh our memory,
لإنعاش ذاكرتنا سريعًا،
when a client publishes a task on a freelancing platform,
عندما ينشر العميل مهمة على منصة للعمل الحر،
a freelancer would send an expression of interest to
يرسل له الموظف الحر رد ليبدي رغبته في العمل
the client and express interest in working on that task.
ويبدي اهتمامه في العمل على المهمة.
Now keep in mind that this is not something long and detailed.
الآن، ضع في الاعتبار أن هذا الرد لا يجب أن يكون طويلًا ومفصلًا.
It is a shot text message sent to the client over the platform
فيجب أن تكون رسالة قصيرة يتم إرسالها للعميل عن طريق المنصة
in about 2-4 lines to express interest in working on that task.
تتراوح الرسالة بين 2- 4 سطور للتعبير عن اهتمامك في العمل على المهمة.
Now let's look at some of the best practices that
الآن دعونا ننظر إلى بعض أفضل الممارسات التي
could be very helpful in winning a project from a client.
يمكن أن تكون مفيدة جدًا لكسب مشروع من عميل.
A lot of these will come naturally to you when you view
الكثير من هذه الأفكار ستأتي إليك بشكل طبيعي عندما ترى
the client's ad and prioritize maximizing value for the client.
إعلان العميل وتعطي الأولوية لتعظيم القيمة للعميل.
First of fall, it is important to reiterate
أولًا، من المهم أن نؤكد على
the understanding of the problem in your own words,
فهم المسألة بطريقتك،
in the expression of interest.
في الرد الخاص بإبداء الرغبة في العمل.
That is the very first thing that you should prioritize.
هذا أول شيء يجب أن تعطيه الأولوية.
This not only helps with getting on the same page with the client,
فهذا يساعدك في أن تُشعر العميل بأنك تفهمه
but it builds trust in the client that you are making an attempt
كما يجعل العميل يثق بأنك تحاول
to get on the same page and fully grasp the problem at hand.
أن تتواصل معه وتفهم احتياجاته من العمل الذي يريد إنجازه.
Now in some cases,
في بعض الأحيان،
if you already have a quick tip for the client to get to the solution,
إذا كان لديك بالفعل معلومة سريعة يمكن أن تنصح بها العميل للوصول إلى الحل،
share it with the client.
فيجب مشاركة ذلك معه.
This will assure the client of your understanding of
هذا سيؤكد للعميل أنك تفهم
the problem and ability to come up with an efficient solution.
المشكلة ولديك القدرة على التوصل إلى حل فعال.
This could also separate you from other freelancers who may not have a quick tip in
يمكن لهذا أيضًا أن يُميزك عن غيرك ممن ليس لديهم حل سريع
their expression of interest or who did not
لعرضه في رسالة إبداء الرغبة في العمل، أو هؤلاء الذين
prioritize sharing it with the client at this point.
لم يعطوا الأولوية لمشاركة الحل مع العميل في هذه المرحلة.
Now again thinking from the client's point of view,
والآن، مرة أخرى فكر من وجهة نظر العميل،
start with the problem statement of the client and not your own credentials.
استهدف مشكلة العميل ولا تبدأ بعرض مؤهلاتك.
Instead of saying that you have x years of experience with the clients,
بدلًا من البدء في التحدث عن سنوات خبرتك مع العملاء،
get straight into the problem statement and how it can be solved.
تحدث مباشرة عن بيان المشكلة وكيف يمكن حلها.
Then backup your claims talking about your skills and experience.
ثم أدعم رؤيتك للحل بالتحدث عن مهاراتك وخبراتك.
You will soon notice that more clients get back to you with this approach since they got
سوف تلاحظ في وقت قصير أن المزيد من العملاء يعودون للعمل معك بفضل هذا الأسلوب، حيث أنهم وجدوا
someone who understands their issue and is already thinking about how to solve it.
شخص يفهم مشكلتهم ويفكر بالفعل في كيفية حلها.
In the end, I would say,
في النهاية، أود أن أقول
consider these as guidelines and not hard rules.
أنه عليك اعتبار ما سبق مبادئ عامة وليست قواعد صارمة.
The more clients you work with,
كلما زاد عدد العملاء الذين تعمل معهم،
better intuition you will develop to deal with different scenarios.
كلما تَكون لديك حدس أفضل يُمَكِنك من التعامل مع السيناريوهات المختلفة.
Now, talking what scenarios,
الآن، وبالحديث عن السيناريوهات،
at the end of this section,
وفي نهاية هذا الجزء،
we will practice writing some expression of interest for
سنمارس كتابة بعض الرسائل الخاصة بإبداء الرغبة في العمل
clients in the exercise that will give us a first-hand experience of it.
مع العملاء، من خلال تمارين لنكتسب خبرة مباشرة في هذا الأمر.
But before that, let's see some examples of fully written expression of interests.
ولكن قبل ذلك دعونا نرى بعض الأمثلة لرسائل التعبير عن الاهتمام والرغبة في العمل.
Now take a look at this example of an expression of interests.
الآن سنلقي نظرة على هذا المثال كرسالة التعبير عن الاهتمام بالعمل.
But before we move forward,
ولكن قبل أن نمضي قدمًا،
I'd encourage you to pause the video here
أرجو منكم إيقاف الفيديو هنا،
and just carefully read through this expression of interest.
وقراءة هذه الرسالة لإبداء الرغبة في العمل.
Think about how the above expression of
فكر كيف تتضمن هذه الرسالة
interest covers the best practices that we discussed earlier.
كل الممارسات التي ناقشناها سابقًا.
You can unpause when you're done.
يمكن أن تستأنف المشاهدة عندما تنتهي.
Now let's evaluate this expression of interest.
والآن هيا نُقيّم هذه الرسالة لإبداء الرغبة في العمل.
We start by reiterating the clients ask at a high level.
نبدأ بالتأكيد على طلب العميل بشكل أكثر تركيزًا.
Are we there? Then we ask a specific question to
هل قمنا بذلك؟ الآن نسأل سؤال محدد
the client mentioning the config file name
للعميل مع ذكر اسم ملف التهيئة "config file"
to check if they already tried working with it.
للتأكد إذا حاول بالفعل العمل به أم لا.
This again demonstrates that you know what you're proposing to work on.
وهذا يؤكد مرة ثانية أنك على علم جيد بالحل الذي تطرحه.
In the third line, we mention explicitly
في السطر الثالث، نذكر بوضوح
about our experience with the technology in question.
خبراتنا السابقة مع التكنولوجيا التي نتحدث عنها.
So far so good,
جيد حتى الآن،
let's try another example.
هيا نجرب مثال آخر.
Again, try pausing the video here to evaluate the expression of interest yourself first.
مرة أخرى عليك إيقاف الفيديو حتى تُقيم بنفسك رسالة إبداء الرغبة في العمل.
All right. In this expression of interest,
حسنًا، في هذه الرسالة لإبداء الرغبة في العمل
we start with talking about
نبدأ بالحديث عن
our extensive experience of working on building web applications,
خبراتنا المكثفة في العمل على إنشاء تطبيقات الشبكات
which is the clients main ask in the job description.
وهو طلب العميل الأساسي في وصفه للوظيفة.
Then we get deeper into the applications and websites that we have built.
ثم نتعمق في التطبيقات والمواقع الإلكترونية التي قمنا بإنشائها.
Then we talk about the client's exact ask followed by a tip for the client,
ثم نتحدث عن طلب العميل بشكل محدد ونُتبع ذلك بمعلومة أو حل سريع للمسألة
demonstrating your expertise in the area as
وتذكر خبراتك السابقة في هذا الجزء،
well as an inclination to make things more efficient for the client.
وإبداء رغبتك في جعل الأمور أكثر كفاءة للعميل.
All this is good except for the fact that we start by talking
كل هذا جيد باستثناء حقيقة أننا نتحدث
about our own experience and not with the client's problem statement.
عن خبراتنا الخاصة أكثر من استهداف مشكلة العميل.
As you send more and more expression of interests,
بينما ترسل المزيد والمزيد من رسائل التعبير عن الاهتمام بالعمل،
you'll notice that the response rate is higher when you start talking
ستلاحظ أن معدل الاستجابة على رسائلك أعلى عندما تبدأ بالكلام
about the client's task at hand first and how you can solve it.
عن مشكلة العميل أولًا وكيف يمكنك حلها.
This immediately catches the eye of the client and this chart, reading attentively.
فهذه الطريقة تلفت نظر العميل على الفور.
You can backup your claims then by talking about
يمكنك دعم ما تذكره بالحديث عن
your skills and experience later in your expression of interest.
مهاراتك وخبراتك لاحقًا في رسالة إبداء الرغبة في العمل.
This is an improved version of the same expression of interest,
وهذه نسخة مُعدلة لرسالة إبداء الرغبة في العمل،
where we start with the reiterating the problem statement at a high level,
حيث نبدأ بالحديث عن المهمة التي يطلبها العميل على مستوى عال،
followed by a tip,
ونتبع الحديث بنصيحة سريعة،
and further followed up by details on our experience and relevant skills.
ثم نتبع ذلك بذكر خبراتنا ومهاراتنا ذات الصلة بالمهمة.